<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">21122351</PMID>
        <DateCreated>
            <Year>2010</Year>
            <Month>12</Month>
            <Day>2</Day>
        </DateCreated>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0253-2727</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>31</Volume>
                    <Issue>6</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2010</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Zhonghua xue ye xue za zhi = Zhonghua xueyexue zazhi</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Zhonghua Xue Ye Xue Za Zhi</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[A proliminary study on the regulatory function of human plasma exosomes-like vesicles.]</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>376-380</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>OBJECTIVE: To identify the exosomes-like vesicles from the plasma and study their biologic characteristics and regulatory effect. METHODS: The exosomes-like vesicles were purified from healthy donors plasma with a series of high-speed centrifugations and ultrafiltration. Morphology was identified by transmission electron microscopy and biologic characteristics by Western blot and flow cytometry. CD4(+)T cells and CD4(+)CD25(+)CD127low Treg cells were purified from peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) by Magnetic cell sorting. After exosomes-like vesicles cultured with CD4(+)T cells or CD4(+)CD25(+)CD127low Treg cells, cell proliferation and apoptosis were assayed. Phosphorylated β-catenin level in Wnt signaling by phosflow. RESULTS: Exosomes-like vesicles from plasma were similar to previously described exosomes in shapes and size and expressed exosome marker proteins CD63 and CD81 as well as the MHC-II molecule, costimulatory molecules CD86 etc. After co-cultured with CD4(+) T cells, exosomes-like vesicles inhibited the proliferation of the T cells in a dose-dependent manner. After Treg cells cultured with exosomes-like vesicles for 14 days, the survival rate of the Treg cells was 57.07%, while that of the control Treg was 30.91%. Frizzled receptors 2, 3, 4and LRP6 gene mRNA expressed (the relative gray value was 48.50, 34.84, 23.85, 49.73) in the Treg cells by RT-PCR, and Wnt molecular expressed in exosomes-like vesicles. After Treg cells co-cultured with exosomes-like vesicles, the MFI of phosphorylated β-catenin decreased (from 20.06 ± 2.99 to 12.41 ± 2.08), and the expression of Bcl-2 mRNA was upregulated significantly (the relative gray value from 0.45 to 84.97). CONCLUSIONS: Exosomes-like vesicles existed in human plasma and express immune regulatory molecules. They can suppress the proliferation of activated CD4(+) T cells induce their apoptosis and pro-long the survival of natural Treg cells via Wnt signaling pathway.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Ma</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Yue-E</ForeName>
                    <Initials>YE</Initials>
                    <Affiliation>Department of Clinical laboratory medicine, Huashan Hospital of Fudan University, Shanghai 200032, China.</Affiliation>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Ren</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Ya-Na</ForeName>
                    <Initials>YN</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Yang</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jie</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Li</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Dan</ForeName>
                    <Initials>D</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Guo</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Chen-Zhi</ForeName>
                    <Initials>CZ</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Guo</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Juan</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Ni</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Bing</ForeName>
                    <Initials>B</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Fan</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Hua-Hua</ForeName>
                    <Initials>HH</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>CHI</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType>JOURNAL ARTICLE</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <MedlineTA>Zhonghua Xue Ye Xue Za Zhi</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>8212398</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0253-2727</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2010</Year>
                <Month>12</Month>
                <Day>3</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2010</Year>
                <Month>12</Month>
                <Day>3</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2010</Year>
                <Month>12</Month>
                <Day>3</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21122351</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>
