<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Owner="NLM" Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE">
        <PMID Version="1">22026976</PMID>
        <DateCreated>
            <Year>2011</Year>
            <Month>11</Month>
            <Day>18</Day>
        </DateCreated>
        <DateCompleted>
            <Year>2011</Year>
            <Month>11</Month>
            <Day>23</Day>
        </DateCompleted>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2012</Year>
            <Month>11</Month>
            <Day>09</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-0500</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>4</Volume>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2011</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>BMC research notes</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>BMC Res Notes</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>A putative diacidic motif in the SARS-CoV ORF6 protein influences its subcellular localization and suppression of expression of co-transfected expression constructs.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>446</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1756-0500-4-446</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The ORF6 protein is one of the eight accessory proteins of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV). Numerous properties of ORF6 have been documented and this study focuses on two of these, namely, its ability to suppress the expression of co-transfected expression constructs and its subcellular localization to vesicular structures.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Using a transient transfection system, ORF6's ability to suppress the expression of co-transfected expression constructs was measured in a quantitative manner. While ORF6 does not have a global effect on protein synthesis, quantitative real-time PCR revealed that it down-regulated the mRNA level of the co-transfected myc-nsp8 gene. Furthermore, alanine substitution of a diacidic cluster motif (aa53-56) in the ORF6 gene caused a reduction in the suppression of expression of co-transfected myc-nsp8 gene. Our previous study revealed that ORF6 localized to vesicular structures in SARS-CoV infected Vero E6 cells. Here, ORF6 was observed to be localized to similar vesicular structures in Vero E6 cells which have been transiently transfected with a mammalian expression plasmid encoding for untagged ORF6. ORF6 showed partial colocalization with cellular proteins CD63 and Lamp1, suggesting that the vesicular structures may be a subpopulation of endosomal/lysosomal vesicles. The alanine substitution of the diacidic cluster motif also altered the subcellular localization of the ORF6 protein, indicating a potential relationship between the subcellular localization of the ORF6 protein and its ability to suppress the expression of co-transfected expression constructs.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">By combining quantitative real-time PCR and transient transfection system, a simple and safe method is established to measure ORF6's ability to suppress the expression of co-transfected myc-nsp8. In addition, immunofluorescence analysis revealed that the subcellular localization of ORF6 when expressed on its own is similar to that observed in SARS-CoV infected cells. Through the use of these two assays, a putative diacidic motif in the ORF6 protein was found to influence its subcellular localization and ability to suppress the expression of co-transfected expression constructs.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Gunalan</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Vithiagaran</ForeName>
                    <Initials>V</Initials>
                    <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University Health System, National University of Singapore, MD4, 5 Science Drive 2, Singapore 117597, Singapore. Yee_Joo_TAN@NUHS.edu.sg.</Affiliation>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Mirazimi</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Ali</ForeName>
                    <Initials>A</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Tan</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Yee-Joo</ForeName>
                    <Initials>YJ</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2011</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>25</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>England</Country>
            <MedlineTA>BMC Res Notes</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101462768</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1756-0500</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherID Source="NLM">PMC3219739</OtherID>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2011</Year>
                <Month>8</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2011</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>25</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="aheadofprint">
                <Year>2011</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>25</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2011</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>27</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2011</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>27</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2011</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>27</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">1756-0500-4-446</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-0500-4-446</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22026976</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3219739</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>
