<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">24988283</PMID>
        <DateCreated>
            <Year>2014</Year>
            <Month>7</Month>
            <Day>2</Day>
        </DateCreated>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">2152-6575</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2014</Year>
                        <Month>Jul</Month>
                        <Day>1</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Allergy &amp; rhinology (Providence, R.I.)</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Allergy Rhinol (Providence)</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Expression of surface markers on the blood cells during the delayed asthmatic response to allergen challenge.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn/>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText NlmCategory="UNLABELLED">Patients with bronchial asthma develop various types of asthmatic response to bronchial challenge with allergen, such as immediate/early asthmatic response (IAR), late asthmatic response (LAR) or delayed asthmatic response (DYAR), because of different immunologic mechanisms. The DYAR, occurring between 24 and 56 hours after the bronchial allergen challenge (p &lt; 0.01), differs from IAR and LAR in clinical as well as immunologic features. This study investigates the expression of CD molecules (markers) on the surface of particular cell populations in the peripheral blood and their changes during the DYAR. In 17 patients developing the DYAR (p &lt; 0.01), the bronchial challenge with allergen was repeated 2?6 weeks later. The repeated DYAR (p &lt; 0.001) was combined with recording of CD molecule expression on various types of blood cells by means of flow cytometry up to 72 hours after the challenge. The results were expressed in percent of the mean relative fluorescence intensity. The DYAR was accompanied by (a) increased expression of CD11b, CD11b/18, CD16,CD32, CD35, CD62E, CD62L, CD64, and CD66b on neutrophils; CD203C on basophils; CD25 and CD62L on eosinophils; CD14, CD16, CD64, and CD86 on monocytes; CD3, CD4, CD8, CD11a, CD18, and CD69 on lymphocytes; CD16, CD56, CD57, and CD94 on natural killer (NK) cells; and CD31, CD41, CD61, CD62P, and CD63 on thrombocytes and (b) decreased expression of CD18 and CD62L on eosinophils, CD15 on neutrophils, and CD40 on lymphocytes. These results suggest involvement of cell-mediated hypersensitivity mechanism, on participation of Th1- lymphocytes, neutrophils, monocytes, NK cells, and thrombocytes in the DYAR.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Pelikan</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Z</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Z</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>ENG</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType>JOURNAL ARTICLE</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2014</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>1</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <MedlineTA>Allergy Rhinol (Providence)</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101570968</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>2152-6567</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2014</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>3</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2014</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>6</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2014</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>6</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">content-00870</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2500/ar.2014.5.0087</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24988283</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4124585</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>
