<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">25177853</PMID>
        <DateCreated>
            <Year>2014</Year>
            <Month>9</Month>
            <Day>1</Day>
        </DateCreated>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0002-5151</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>61</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2014 Jul-Sep</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Revista alergia Mexico (Tecamachalco, Puebla, Mexico : 1993)</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Rev Alerg Mex</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Effect of immunotherapy on basophil activation induced by allergens in patients with atopic dermatitis.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>168-77</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Subcutaneous allergen-specific immunotherapy (IT) is a proved, highly effective treatment for respiratory IgE-mediated diseases. However, few studies have explored the immunological mechanisms of IT in patients with atopic dermatitis.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To explore the immune response of atopic dermatitis patients receiving house dust mite (HDM) immunotherapy, according to humoral response and basophil activation.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">An open label study was done which assessed the severity of atopic dermatitis with SCORAD in 20 patients (10 with immunotherapy and 10 without it) every three months during two years. Serum samples were taken before the follow up, and at the first and second year of study to analyze CD63 basophil expression, total IgE levels and specific IgE and IgG4 to Der p and Der f. Ten patients with allergic rhinitis receiving IT and 5 non-allergic subjects were used as controls.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">CD63 expression after basophil stimulation with Der p was higher in atopic dermatitis patients than in rhinitis and non-allergic subjects. After the first and second year of treatment, CD63 expression was lower in atopic dermatitis active group than in the atopic dermatitis control group. We observed a correlation between SCORAD, IgG4 and CD63 expression.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In patients with atopic dermatitis, basophil activation test could be a biomarker of clinical response and basophil modulation can result in a better clinical control.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>S치nchez</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jorge</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                    <Affiliation>Group of Clinical and Experimental Allergy. IPS Universitaria, University of Antioquia, Medellin, Colombia. Foundation for the Development of Medical and Biological Sciences (FUNDEMEB), Cartagena, Colombia. Institute for Immunological Research, University of Cartagena, Cartagena, Colombia. jotamsc@yahoo.com.</Affiliation>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Cardona</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Ricardo</ForeName>
                    <Initials>R</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>ENG</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType>JOURNAL ARTICLE</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Efecto de la inmunoterapia en la activaci칩n de bas칩filos inducida por alergenos en pacientes con dermatitis at칩pica.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <MedlineTA>Rev Alerg Mex</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9438824</NlmUniqueID>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="SPA">
            <AbstractText>Abstract available from the publisher.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Allergy</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atopy</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Basophil</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dermatitis</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eczema</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunotherapy</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2014</Year>
                <Month>9</Month>
                <Day>2</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2014</Year>
                <Month>9</Month>
                <Day>2</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2014</Year>
                <Month>9</Month>
                <Day>2</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25177853</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>
